A Finding Aid to the Walter Pach Papers, 1857-1980, in the Archives of American Art AAA.pachwalt2
Archives of American Art
- Writings, 1899-circa 1950s; Series 3; 2.5 Linear feet Box 3-5
  - Writings by Others, circa 1910-circa 1950s; 3.2
    - Authors: Unidentified, circa 1910-circa 1950s (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Authors: Various, Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion, 1940s-1950s (Box 5, Folder 28-29)
- Diaries and Journals, 1903-circa 1950s; Series 4; 5 Folders Box 5
  Of particular note is a travel diary, dated 1903-1904, recording Pach's trips to Europe with William Merritt Chase's class. The entries include reflections on life abroad, fellow classmates Morton Livingston Schamberg and Charles Sheeler, Pach's early interest in Japonisme and active collecting of Japanese art, including prints by master ukiyo-e artists Hokusai and Hiroshige, and the purchase in Holland of a Manga book (an artist's instructional manual) by Hokusai.
  Also included here is a folder of addresses recording Pach's contacts in Mexico in 1942-1943 and an address book with journal entries made during a UNESCO Congress of Critics in Paris, circa 1948.
  A "Shelley Birthday Book" notes birthdays of Pach family members and friends.
  - Addresses and Diary, UNESCO Congress of Critics in Paris, circa 1948 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Addresses, "Mexico 1942-1943" (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Journal, 1903-1904 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Journal, Loose Pages, 1904 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - "Shelley Birthday Book", circa 1950s (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Business Records, circa 1913-circa 1960s; Series 5; 0.3 Linear feet Box 5-6
  Of particular note in this series are two record books: one in which Pach recorded sales for the Armory Show, New York beginning February 18th and ending March 15, 1913, listing the person purchasing each picture and the amount paid, and "signed off" with the inscription "OK" and the initials "JM," presumably Jerome Myers; the second in which Pach recorded sales for the Armory Show in Boston and Chicago beginning March 23 and ending April 30, 1913, also signed off by "JM."
  Other items of note include an "agenda" book from 1930-1932 which contains lists of paintings owned and sold by Pach in addition to what appears to be an inventory of his belongings, including contents of the Pach apartment; and two record books containing a "record of pictures, writings and lectures," notes on "pictures sold, exchanged or presented," and a list of "places where I have lectured." The books cover the years 1903-1950s.
  One folder contains consignment lists for Pach's paintings and etchings at Kraushaar Galleries and E. Weyhe in 1934.
  A record book belonging to Nikifora Pach contains notes on loans and sales of pictures in the late 1950s, in addition to enclosures documenting loan and consignment transactions with Zabriskie Gallery, the Museum of Modern Art, and others in the early 1960s. Also found is a photocopy of a list of paintings belonging to Pach and given to Nikifora Pach in the 1950s.
  The bulk of this series has been scanned. Routine personal business records including life and medical insurance records, property and tax records and financial and legal papers relating to Raymond Pach, have not been scanned.
  - Account Books, 1930-1958 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - "Agenda" Book Listing Paintings Owned and Sold by Pach, 1930-1932 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Bank Statements and Receipts, circa 1950s (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Consignment Lists, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Financial and Legal Papers, Magda and Raymond Pach, 1939-1950 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Income Tax Records, 1946-1952 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Insurance, Life and Medical, 1924-1958 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Insurance, Property, 1937-1943 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Investment Records, 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Library of Congress Cards and Copyright Certificates, circa 1913 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - List of Books, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Lists of Paintings by/belonging to Pach Given to Nikifora Pach (photocopies), 1951-1958 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Medical Expenses/Records, 1948-1957 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Notebook Recording Sales at the Armory Show, New York, 1913 February-March (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Notebook Recording Sales at the Armory Show, Boston, Chicago, 1913 March-April (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Property Records, 1930s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Record Book of Nikifora Pach, 1950s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Records of Pictures Sold, Lectures and Publications, circa 1903-circa 1962 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Printed Material, circa 1900-1977; Series 6; 1.3 Linear feet Box 6-7, 9
  Printed material relating to Pach and others, includes rare exhibition announcements and catalogs such as a 1913 Boston Armory Show catalog annotated with prices, printed articles by Pach and about him including book reviews of his work, reproductions of artwork including postcards from the 1913 Armory Show, news clippings and miscellany.
  The bulk of this series has been scanned with the exception of duplicates and the complete texts of some publications for which only the cover and relevant pages have been scanned.
  6.1: Pach Printed Material, 1907-1959
  6.2: Other Printed Material, circa 1900-1977
  - Pach Printed Material, 1907-1959; 6.1
    Printed material by Pach includes announcements and exhibition catalogs for Pach's solo and group exhibitions, including a a 1913 annotated Boston Armory Show catalog. Also found are two booklets written by Pach and published on the occasion of the Armory Show: A Sculptor's Architecture, and Odilon Redon.
    Also found here is an almost complete collection of Pach's published articles in the form of the pages from the journals, magazines, and newspapers in which they appeared, including Scribner's Magazine, Dial, Shadowland, Parnassus, and 35 columns writtten for The Freeman between 1920 and 1924.
    - About Pach, 1910-1959 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Exhibition Catalog, Armory Show, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Group Exhibitions, 1907-1914 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Group Exhibitions, 1915-1920 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Group Exhibitions, circa 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Solo Exhibitions, 1925-1928 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Solo Exhibitions, 1931-1935 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Solo Exhibitions, 1936-1947 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Lecture Announcements, Pach, 1906-1951 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Published Writings by Pach (Box 6)
      - Armory Show, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Exhibition Catalogs, circa 1930s (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Journal/Magazine Articles, circa 1910-circa 1950s (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Journal/Magazine Articles, 1907-1910 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Journal/Magazine Articles, 1911-1912 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Journal/Magazine Articles, 1913-1919 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Journal/Magazine Articles, 1920-1924 (Box 6, Folder 20-21)
      - Journal/Magazine Articles, 1926-1929 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Journal/Magazine Articles, 1932-1940 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Journal/Magazine Articles, 1952-1958 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Newspaper Articles, 1916-1948 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Reviews of Books by Pach, 1924-1959 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Other Printed Material, circa 1900-1977; 6.2
    The bulk of this series has been scanned with the exception of duplicates and the full text of certain publications for which only the cover and relevant pages have been scanned.
    Other printed material includes announcements and exhibition catalogs for artists other than Pach as well as for a 1937 Pach Brothers exhibition "American Personalities Through Seven Decades," news clippings on subjects of apparent interest to Pach, postcards from the Armory Show and other reproductions of artwork.
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, circa 1907-1910 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1911-1912 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1913-1916 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1919-1920 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1922-1929 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, circa 1930-1942 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1943-1946 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, Pach Brothers, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1890s-circa 1960s (Box 6, Folder 35-36)
      Oversized material housed in Box 9, Folder 4
    - News Clippings, General, circa 1900-circa 1970s (Box 6, Folder 37)
      Oversized material housed in Box 9, Folder 5
    - News Clippings, General, circa 1907-1913 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - News Clippings, General, 1914-1957 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - News Clippings, General, 1966-1977 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Postcards, Armory Show, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Postcards of Artwork, circa 1910-circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Reproductions of Artwork, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Oversized material housed in Box 9 Folder 6
    - Travel Booklets, circa 1900-circa 1920 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Oversized, Miscellaneous, circa 1890s-circa 1960s (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Oversized material scanned with Box 6, Folder 36
    - Oversized, News Clippings, General, circa 1900-circa 1970s (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Oversized material scanned with Box 6, Folder 37
    - Oversized Reproductions of Artwork, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Oversized material scanned with Box 7, Folder 3
- Scrapbooks, circa 1890-circa 1940s; Series 7; 0.4 Linear feet Box 7, 9
  Scrapbooks include a dismantled scrapbook of reviews and original letters relating to Pach's book Ananias or the False Artist, published in 1928. Also housed here is a scrapbook primarily documenting Pach's activities during the 1920s which included his first one-man show at the Brummer Gallery in New York City and the publication of his books Masters of Modern Art and Raymond Duchamp-Villon. The scrapbook contains news clippings with press reviews of Pach's work.
  A scrapbook of musical and theatrical events and programs includes a program for a 1917 Neighorhood Playhouse production of a Wallace Stevens's play, Bowl, Cat and Broomstick, for which Pach designed the sets. Also found is a guestbook from an unidentified event.
  - Ananias or the Bad Artist, Contents of Scrapbook, 1928-1935 (Box 7, Folder 5-7)
  - Ananias or the Bad Artist, Additional News Clippings, 1928-1935 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Guest Book of Unidentified Event, circa 1920s-circa 1940s (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Oversized material housed in Box 9, Folder 7
  - Scrapbook of the 1920s, circa 1913-1920s (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Oversized material housed in Box 9, Folder 8
  - Scrapbook of Musical and Theatrical Events and Programs, circa 1890-circa 1930s (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Oversized Guest Book of Unidentified Event, circa 1920s-circa 1940s (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 7, Folder 9
  - Oversized Scrapbook of the 1920s, circa 1913-1920s (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 7, Folder 10
- Artwork, circa 1860-circa 1950s; Series 8; 0.4 Linear feet Box 7, 10
  This series consists of a small group of loose drawings and three early sketchbooks by Pach, plus several drawings by unidentified artists. Also included are two print portfolios published in 1947 by the Laurel Gallery, New York City; one includes an essay by Pach and the other an etching by Pach. These portfolios include hand-pulled prints by artists such as Milton Avery, Reginald Marsh, and Joan Miro.
  - By Pach, Drawings, circa 1920s-circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - By Pach, Sketchbooks, circa 1920s-circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 13-15)
  - By Pach and Others, Laurel Gallery Portfolios, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folder 1
  - By Others, Miniature Portrait of Frances Wise (Pach's mother), circa 1860s (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - By Others, Unidentified Artists, circa 1920s-circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Oversized By Pach and Others, Laurel Gallery Portfolios, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 7, Folder 16
- Photographs, 1857-1959; Series 9; 1.4 Linear feet Box 7-8, 10
  This series includes photographs of Pach, his family, and artists/friends, as well as group pictures of William Merritt Chase's class, Robert Henri's class at the New York School of Art, circa 1904, and others. There are also photographs of works of art by Pach and others. Of special interest is a group of photographs of mural projects in Mexico by José Clemente Orozco and Diego Rivera.
  The series is arranged as 2 subseries.
  9.1: Photographs of People and Places, 1857-1959
  9.2: Photographs of Artwork, circa 1907-circa 1950s
  - Photographs of People and Places, 1857-1959; 9.1
    This series has been scanned in entirety with the exception of negatives and duplicates.
    This series includes photographs of Pach from boyhood to the 1950s, including portraits, photos with family members, in his studio and apartment, in group photos and with artists and friends, including Florence Arquin and Diego Rivera. Included is a series of photos by Hansel Mieth of Pach in his studio and with Magda Pach in their home listening to Raymond Pach playing the piano.
    Photos of others include the following artists and friends: Edith Bell, William Merritt Chase, Raymond Duchamp-Villon, Thomas Eakins, Arthur B. Frost, Jr., Carl Hauser, Robert Henri, Inna Khabroff, Susan McDonnel, Moriye Ogihara, Pablo Picasso, Eda Puckhaber, and General and Mrs. Webb.
    Also of note is a collection of photographs of Pach's apartment, art collection and studio, circa 1959.
    - Of Pach, Portraits, circa 1900-circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 19-20)
      Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folder 2
    - Of Pach and Pach Family, circa 1880-1920s (Box 7, Folder 21-22)
    - Of Pach and Pach Family-Daguerrotype of Pach's Mother and Grandparents, 1857 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Of Pach and Pach Family, Magda Pach, circa 1890-circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Of Pach and Pach Family, Raymond Pach and Others, circa 1930-circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Of Pach with Florence Arquin and Diego Rivera, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Of Pach and Groups Pictures of Artists/Friends, circa 1904-circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Of Pach and Others, Unidentified, circa 1940s (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Of Others, Artists and Friends, circa 1870-1953 (Box 7, Folder 29-30)
    - Of Others, Group of Artists by Durand-Ruel, circa 1920s (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Of Others, William Merritt Chase European Summer School, Madrid, Spain?, circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 32-33)
    - Of Others, Mexican Dancers, circa 1940s (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Of Others, Unidentified, circa 1900-circa 1940s (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Of Buildings/Engineering Projects, 1919-1922 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Of a House, Inscribed "From Ruth and Arthur", 1947 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Of Installations, Society of Independent Artists, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Of Pach Apartment, Art Collection and Studio, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 39-41)
    - Of Pach Apartment, Art Collection and Studio, Negatives and Duplicates, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Of Pach House, Brewster, NY, circa 1940s (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Of Still Life signed by Sidney Waintraub, circa 1940 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Oversized of Pach, Portraits, circa 1900-circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Oversized material scanned with Box 7 Folder 19
    - Oversized of Pach and Family, circa 1880-circa 1920s (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Oversized material scanned with Box 7, Folder 22
    - Oversized of Pach and Family, Raymond Pach and Others, circa 1930-circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Oversized material from Box 7, Folder 25
    - Oversized of Pach and Group Pictures of Artists/Friends, circa 1904-circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Oversized material from Box 7, Folder 27
    - Oversized of Others, Unidentified, circa 1900-circa 1940s (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Oversized material from Box 7, Folder 35
  - Photographs of Artwork, circa 1907-circa 1950s; 9.2
    This series includes photographs of artwork by Pach, Magda Pach and others including a group showing mural projects in Mexico by José Clemente and Diego Rivera, and photos of artwork by Antoine-Louis Barye and George amongst others. Also found is a photographic print and a slide of a model by Raymond Duchamp-Villon, labeled "Facade of a city residence (Model shown at the International Exhibition)" (the Armory Show) by an unknown photogapher; and a series of photographs used for Pach's book The Art Museum in America.
    This bulk of this series has been scanned. Negatives and duplicates have not been scanned.
    - By Pach, Walter, circa 1907-circa 1956 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - By Pach, Walter, circa 1907-circa 1919 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - By Pach, Walter, circa 1922-circa 1929 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - By Pach, Walter, circa 1930-circa 1931 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - By Pach, Walter, circa 1932-circa 1931 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - By Pach, Walter, circa 1937-circa 1944 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - By Pach, Walter, circa 1946-circa 1956 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - By Pach, Walter, Negatives, circa 1907-circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - By Others, Barye, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 10-12)
    - By Others: Bay-Dali, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 13)
      Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folder 3
    - By Others: Delacroix, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - By Others: Drewes-Duchamp-Villon, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 15)
      includes one photographic print and one slide of "Facade of a city residence (Model shown at the International Exhibition)" (the Armory Show) by an unknown photographer.
    - By Others: Duchamp-Villon, Raymond, "Facade of a city residence (model shown at the International Exhibition)" (Armory Show), Print and Slide, circa 1913 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - By Others: Evergood-Hiller, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - By Others: Ingres-Of, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - By Others: Orozco, José Clemente, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - By Others: Pach, Magda, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 20-21)
    - By Others: Pineda-Riportella, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - By Others: Rivera, Diego, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 23-24)
    - By Others: Robus-Rubens, circa 1920s-circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - By Others: Tovish-Van Gogh, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - By Others: Villon, Jacques-Wickey, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - By Others: Unidentified, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 28-31)
    - By Others: Unidentified, Negatives, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - By Others: for "The Art Museum in America", circa 1940s (Box 8, Folder 33-34)
    - Oversized Photos of Artwork by Others: Bay-Dali, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Oversized material scanned with Box 8, Folder 13
    - Oversized Photos of Artwork by Others: Ingres-Of, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Oversized material scanned with Box 8, Folder 18
    - Oversized Photos of Artwork by Others: Tovish-Van Gogh, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Oversized material scanned with Box 8, Folder 26
    - Oversized Photos of Artwork by Others: Unidentified, circa 1920-circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Oversized material scanned with Box 8, Folder 31
- Selections from Walter Pach's Library, 1880-1963; Series 10; 12 Linear feet Box 11-22
  This series houses selected publications from Walter Pach's libary and include books or publications annotated by him, and written or translated by him. Also found here are items considered to be central to Pach's interests and work.
  10.1: Works Written by Walter Pach, 1901-1956
  10.2: Works Translated by Walter Pach, 1918-1950
  10.3: Selected Publications, 1880-1963
  This series is arranged as 3 subseries. Catalogs that appear in this series appear under museum, gallery, or auction house name, unless an individual is cited as author.
  This series has not been scanned.
  - Works Written by Walter Pach, 1901-1956; 10.1
    - American Artist (New York) 12, no. 8, 1948 October (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Includes "The Past Lives On," by Walter Pach, pp. 28-31, 64-66.
    - American Artist (New York) 12, no. 9, 1948 November (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Includes second installment of "The Past Lives On," by Walter Pach, pp. 40-43, 64.
    - L'Amour de l'Art (Paris), no. 6, 1930 June. (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Includes "Notes sur le classicisme de Delacroix," by Walter Pach, pp. 241-253.
    - L'Amour de l'Art (Paris) 13, no. 9, 1932 November (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Includes "Le classicisme de Barye," by Walter Pach, pp. 319-320.
    - Anderson Galleries. Two Masterpieces of Renaissance Painting from the Collection of Carl W. Hamilton. New York, 1929. (Box 11, Folder 5)
      Includes "Extract from an Article on the Half-Century Celebration at the Metropolitan Museum of Art, by Walter Pach in The Freeman," p. 10.
    - Art in America (Springfield, Mass.) 31, no. 1, 1943 January. (Box 11, Folder 6)
      Includes "A Newly Found American Painter," by Walter Pach, pp. 32-43.
    - Art from Life to Life by Abraham Walkowitz. Girard, Kans.: Haldeman-Julius Publications, 1951. (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Includes "Walkowitz and Tradition," an appreciation by Walter Pach.
    - Art News (New York) 45, no. 5, 1946 July (Box 11, Folder 8)
      Includes " La Barricade in America," by Walter Pach, pp. 42-43, 60.
    - Art News (New York) 48, no. 3, 1949 May. (Box 11, Folder 9)
      Includes "Thus Is Cubism Cultivated," by Walter Pach and Jacques Villon, pp. 23-25, 52-53.
    - Art News (New York) 55, no. 6, 1956 October. (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Includes "Introducing the Paintings of George Of, 1876-1954," by Walter Pach, pp. 36-38, 62-63. Two copies.
    - Arts (New York) 3, no. 3, 1923 March. (Box 11, Folder 11)
      Includes "Georges Seurat," by Walter Pach, pp. 160-174.
    - Brummer Gallery. Brancusi. Introduction by Paul Morand. New York, 1926 November 17-December 15. (Box 11, Folder 12)
      Includes article by Walter Pach.
    - Bryson, Lyman, and Louis Finkelstein, eds. Science, Philosophy and Religion, Second Symposium. New York: Conference of Science, Philosophy and Religion in Their Relation to the Democratic Way of Life, Inc., 1942. (Box 11, Folder 13)
      Includes "The Artist and the Democratic Way of Life," by Walter Pach, pp. 493-505.
    - Bryson, Lyman, Louis Finkelstein, and R. M. MacIver, eds. Perspectives on a Troubled Decade: Science, Philosophy, and Religion, 1939-1949. Symposium. New York and London: Harper & Brothers, 1950. (Box 11, Folder 14)
      Includes "The Stake of the Arts in the Democratic Way of Life: A Postscript," by Walter Pach, pp. 743-755.
    - Bulletin of the Springfield Museum of Fine Arts (Springfield, Mass.) 21, no. 4, 1955 April-May (Box 11, Folder 15)
      Includes "The Portrait of a Painter," by Walter Pach, pp. 2-3.
    - Campbell, Vivian, ed. A Christmas Anthology of Poetry and Painting. Foreword by Walter Pach. New York: Woman's Press, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Century 87, no. 6, 1914 April. (Box 11, Folder 17)
      Includes "The Point of View of the Moderns," by Walter Pach, pp. 851-864.
    - Creative Art: A Magazine of Fine and Applied Art (New York) 11, no. 3., 1932 November. (Box 11, Folder 18)
      Includes "Marinot, Artist and Artisan," by Walter Pach, and a caricature of him by Aline Fruhauf, p. 203.
    - Dial (New York) 68, no. 1, 1920 January. (Box 11, Folder 19)
      Includes "The Art of the American Indian," by Walter Pach, pp. 57-65.